SOUNDARYA

SKILLS

Programming

Python · SQL · R · Java · Scala

Data

Pipelines · ETL Pipelines · MySQL ·

Data Analysis • Big data • Hive • Spark •

Hadoop · MapReduce · Pig · Kafka ·

Talend · MongoDB · Oracle

Cloud

AWS · Azure · Cloud Security

STRENGTHS

Communication Skills

Able to boil down complex subjects to juniors. Patient, understanding, willing to help, is how my colleagues describe

Creativity

I put all my creative effort into finding a solution.

Result-oriented

I always make sure my team is on the right path.

Senior Data Engineer

📞 8984080971 . @ soundarya@gmail.com 🕜 github.io/soundarya . 🗣 chennai

SUMMARY

Senior Data Engineer with 10+ years of experience in building data intensive applications, tackling challenging architectural and scalability problems, collecting and sorting data in the healthcare field. Currently, helping BurnBright to become the first company to fully understand burnouts and start providing custom solutions to its users.

EDUCATION

B.S. Computer Science

2005 - 2009

Texas A&M University

College Station, TX

GPA 3.8 / 4.0

EXPERIENCE

Senior Data Engineer

2019 - Present

Austin, TX

BurnBright

BurnBright is an Austin, TX based company focused on researching burnouts and providing custom solution to users.

- Leading a team of 10 data scientists & acquisition engineers
- Analyzed converted legacy EMR (Electronic Medical Record) data for Epic EMR compatibility
- Decreased database load by ~26% by refactoring data structures and implementing an undate on event cache
- Developed an ETL system to replace an existing data pipeline built on DTS using Python 2.7 and SQL Server

Data Engineer

2014 - 2019

Reilly Group

Austin, TX

Reilly Group is a Khosla Ventures backed company focusing on behavioral mental healthcare.

- Developed Pig scripts for data analysis and perform transformation
- Collected 3000 sets of facial expression, gesture, and speech data, and processed it with MapReduce
- Introduced several reusable generic Talent systems that allowed saves up to 50% on development time

Data Engineer

2011 - 2014

Microbiome Foundation

Austin, TX

Microbiome Foundation is a biotechnology company based in San Francisco that has developed technology to sequence the human microbiomes.

- Automated ETL processes, making it easier to wrangle data and reducing time by as much as 40%
- Increased the efficiency of the data fetching by approximately 30% using query optimization and indexing
- Implemented Cloud Security and Data Loss Protection
- Used Scala to store streaming data to HDFS and to implement Spark for faster processing of data (40% faster)